Miscellaneous Benjamin Franklin Collections 1710-1822 Mss.B.F85.misc
American Philosophical Society
Miscellaneous Benjamin Franklin Collections
1710-1822
Mss.B.F85.misc
American Philosophical Society
5.0 Linear feet
Since publication of I. Minis Hays's Calendar of the Papers of Benjamin Franklin in 1908, the APS Library has acquired a large number of miscellaneous letters and other documents relating to the life, mind, and work of Franklin and his immediate family. The collections listed in this finding aid consist of letters and documents to and from Franklin organized into groupings based upon provenance or focal point. The largest grouping consists of miscellaneous materials acquired individually or in small groups over the years, including a number of important individual items. The other collections consist largely of correspondence between Franklin and individual friends and colleagues, including his friends Mme Brillon, Mary "Polly" Stevenson Hewson, and Catherine Ray Greene, the Whig agriculturist Richard Jackson, and the printer Francis Childs. The collections include photostats of selected materials held by other institutions or that were in private hands. These are available for reference only.
733 items
Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
Scope and Contents note
Since publication of I. Minis Hays's Calendar of the Papers of Benjamin Franklin in 1908, the APS Library has acquired a large number of miscellaneous letters and other documents relating to the life, mind, and work of Franklin and his immediate family. The collections listed in this finding aid consist of letters and documents to and from Franklin organized into groupings based upon provenance or focal point. The largest grouping consists of miscellaneous materials acquired individually or in small groups over the years, including a number of important individual items. The other collections consist largely of correspondence between Franklin and individual friends and colleagues, including his friends Mme Brillon, Mary "Polly" Stevenson Hewson, and Catherine Ray Greene, the Whig agriculturist Richard Jackson, and the printer Francis Childs.
The letters to and from Benjamin Franklin in the miscellaneous collections has been or will be published by the Papers of Benjamin Franklin project. For the most part these materials arrived after I. Minis Hays undertook his project to calendar the Franklin Papers, and as a result, are not included in that calendar. The current Miscellaneous Collection is the product of the merger of three separate miscellaneous collections previously identified only by differences in call number. The items in each of these miscellaneous collections were originally catalogued in the order received and were assigned a numerical suffix to the basic call number (e.g. B F85.200 or B F85x.1). Although the collection has been rearranged into a single chronological series, we have retained the original call numbers to facilitate comparison to earlier citations.
The Library has holds reference copies of Franklin correspondence held at Abercairny House, General Registry Office, Edinburgh (correspondence with Henry Homes, Lord Kames), the J. Pierpont Morgan Library, the Harkness Collection at the New York Public Library, and the Bibliothèque Municipale, Mantes, France (duc de La Rochefoucauld). These materials may not be copied without the prior permission of the institution holding the originals.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Acquired variously.
Related Archival Materials note
Other Benjamin Franklin Collections
Benjamin Franklin Papers
View Collection
Franklin-Bache Papers
View Collection
James S. and Frances M. Bradford Collection
View Collection
Naval History Note
The Miscellaneous Benjamin Franklin Collections contain a few items which may be on interest to naval historians:
Barry, John, 1745-1803.
Franklin, Benjamin. Letter to Captain John Barry. 1782 January 24. Concerning finding sailors for Captain Barry. Will see the Marquis de la Fayette about procuring some French sailors for service. Americans who have recently escaped from or have been exchanged from English prisons are also a possibility. The consul Mr. Barclay should be approached for anything that is needed for the ship. 1 page. (B F85.150)
Jones, John Paul, 1747-1792.
Franklin, Benjamin. Letter to M. Le Ray de Chaumont. 1779 August 5. Regarding orders for Captain John Paul Jones. 1 page. (B F85.29).
Franklin, Benjamin. Letter to Mrs. Jane Meacom (sic). 1779 October 25. Regarding the activities of John Paul Jones along the English coast. 4 pages. Jane Mecom Collection (B F85.m).
Lee, Stephen. Letter to Benjamin Franklin. 1780 February 1. Complains of ill-treatment from John Paul Jones. Wishes payment for his services. 2 pages. (B F85.x67).
Huntington, Samuel. Letter to Benjamin Franklin. 1781 March 2. Enclosing resolutions of the Congress pertaining to John Paul Jones. 1 page. (B F85.x42).
Early American History Note
The Papers of Benjamin Franklin are a rich source as varied and expansive as Dr. Franklin’s storied life. The Collection has been calendared, catalogued, and much of it is available online at franklinpapers.org and in printed volumes. The APS inventory in MOLE is extraordinarily detailed. The aim of this entry is not to reproduce what is already readily accessible, but to focus on material that is unavailable in printed or online sources.
Most notable are a series of bound volumes that capture different aspects of Franklin’s professional career. The bound volumes include a nearly complete record of the colonial Post Office that Franklin headed, numerous account books from Franklin’s time in England and France, and official account books of the U.S. mission in France. In addition to these bound account and ledger books, the collection also includes a copy of the earliest deed known deed for the Pennsylvania statehouse property, various sketches and drawings thought to be done by Franklin, and four large volumes of a journal of John Lindsay Crawford’s travels with the Russian Army from 1737-1739 that include large maps of Europe that Franklin kept in his library (these four volumes are separately described in MOLE under Crawford).
The Franklin Papers, along with the papers of his grandsons at the APS, provide a nearly complete picture of Benjamin’s time in France as an American ambassador to France during the American Revolution. Aside from the manuscript records from this period, the collection has a nearly complete set of account books detailing both the official and personal transactions of Franklin in France.
The APS also houses a collection of books that came from Franklin’s personal library. The library offers insight into Franklin’s own reading and intellectual life. A box of miscellaneous papers in the manuscript collection may also be of related research interest. This box includes a variety of documents that Franklin had in his possession, such as copies of newspapers that have marginalia, that are not included in the official published papers.
American Philosophical Society.; Bache, Sarah Franklin, 1743-1808; Bingham, William, 1752-1804; Brillon, Mme; Chaumont, Jacques-Donatien Leray de, 1725-1803; Childs, Francis, 1763-1830; Cook, James, 1728-1779; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774; Franklin, William Temple, 1760-1823; Franklin, William, 1731-1813; Galloway, Joseph, 1731-1803; Genet, Edme Jacques, d.1781; Greene, Catherine Ray, 1731-1794; Greene, William, 1731-1809; Hall, David, 1714-1772; Hartley, David, ca.1730-1817; Helvetius, Anne Catherine de Ligniville d'Autricourt, 1719-1800; Hewson, Mary Stevenson, 1734-1795; Hill, Henry, 1732-1798; Ingersoll, Jared, 1722-1781; Jackson, Richard, ca.1721-1787; Jay, John, 1745- 1829; Junto; Laurens, Henry, 1724-1792; Le Roy, Jean Baptiste; Lee, Arthur, 1740-1792; Mecom, Jane Franklin, 1712-1794; Price, Richard, 1723-1791; Stevenson, Margaret, ca.1706-1763; Strahan, William, 1715-1785; Vergennes, Charles Gravier, comte de, 1717-1787; Waring, John, 1716-1794; Williams, Jonathan.; Wistar, Caspar, 1761-1818; African Americans--Education; Electricity--Early works to 1800; France--Foreign relations--United States; Great Britain--Foreign relations--United States; Pennsylvania--Politics and government--Colonial period, ca.1600-1775; Postal service--United States; Printers--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia; Stamp Act, 1765; United States--Foreign relations--France; United States--Foreign relations--Great Britain; United States--History--Colonial period, ca.1600-1775; United States--History--French and Indian War, 1755-1763; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783--Causes
- Benjamin Franklin Miscellaneous Collection, 1710-1793; Mss.B.F85.[numeral]; 531 items
  Scope and Contents note
  Miscellaneous manuscripts written by or to Benjamin Franklin, acquired individually or in small groups. The material spans the entirety of Franklin's public career. A few items are supplied in photocopy from originals held privately or at other institutions.
  The collection was rearranged chronologically in 2003, however the individual item numbers have been retained for reference purposes.
  - Poems to B[enjamin] F[ranklin], 1710 July 7, 15; Photocopy,1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Immediate Source of Acquisition note
    From originals in Julia Rush Biddle Henry Coll., Rosenbach Found.
  - Elegy on my Sister Franklin, [ca. 1718-1722].; Photostat, 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in possession of the University of Pennsylvania. See University of Pennsylvania Library chronicle, v.2,no.3 and v.8,2-3.
    Bibliography
    See Labaree, Papers, I, 46,47.
  - Will, 1732/33 January 16; DS, 1p.; Cash, Caleb
    Witnessed: B. Franklin, Stephen Potts, Sarah Read. Certification, April 26, 1737, S: Pet[er] Evans.
  - Proposals and queries for the Junto, [ca.1732].; Photo., 5p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In hand of Charles Thomson
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    From original in the Thomson memorandum book, 1754-1774. Gratz collection, H.S.P.
    Printed: Labaree, Papers, 255-259.
    See Film 476 for copy from Franklin's Commonplace book
  - Lease to Sarah Read for house and lot on High Street, for 99 years, 1734 April 11; Photostat of DS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
    Printed: Labaree, Papers I, 367ff.
  - Lease to Sarah Read, 1734 April 11; DS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Morris Duane; Dec.1969.
    Printed: Labaree, Papers, I, 367-370.
  - Power of attorney, in the name of her husband Benjamin Franklin, to James Wilson to collect mortgage money from estate of William Maugridge, 1738 Oct. 14; D.S. 1p.; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
    Att: Nicholas Waln [and] John Patton.
  - Indenture to William Maugridge for the lease of a plot of ground in Northern Liberties, adjacent to that of Benjamin Franklin, 1741 March 10; DS, 1p.; Coates, William
    Certification, June 27, 1776;S: Jacob Duché.
  - Will, 1741 March 9; D.S. 2p.; Edgell, Simon
    Seal Witnessed: B. Franklin et al
  - Account with John Read, 1741 April 20-1743 Sept. 26; 1749 October 23; DS, 1p.; Koyle, Michael. Estate
    Contains receipt, same date, written in B. Franklin's (executor of estate) hand S: John Read.
  - [Bond in re administration of estate of Simon Edgell], 1743 April 2; DS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Proposal for promoting useful knowledge among the British plantations in America, 1743 May 14; DS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In hand of Alexander Garden (?)
    Copy sent to the Royal Society of arts, London, by Alexander Garden; cf. William Shipley to BF, Sept. 13, 1755 - Franklin Papers I,38; also
  - Bond of Edward Smout, Rebecca Edgell and Benjamin Franklin in re estate of John Armstrong, 1744 April 24; DS, 1p.; Smout, Edward
  - Receipt to John Bringhurst for printing Mr. Estaugh's book, with statement of account of Elizabeth Estaugh and John Bringhurst, 1744 April 25; Photocopy,2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Willman Spawn; 1966.
    (from originals in Estaugh Papers, Haverford College, quaker Collection.)
  - Letter to Cadwallader Colden, 1744 April 5; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Relative to founding of the APS.
    From original in possession of New-York Historical Society.
  - Letter to W[illia]m Strahan, 1744 Sept. 18; ALS, 1p. Slightly mutilated.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Sends books he has printed. Orders type to complete a "little Printing House for our common Friend Mr. Hall."
    Printed: Labaree, Papers, II, 416-417.
  - Account with [Nathaniel] Clapp (sic), [1744 November 3]; ADS Cy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Charges for printing and binding Mather's Soul-saying gospel truths. On same page as B[enjamin] Franklin to Clapp (sic); [Nov.3, 1744,]
    (From Bruce Gimelson, Autograph Auction No. 8, October 5, 1972.)
  - Post-master's bill; from the post-office at Philad. to the post-office at Boston, 1745 June 13; Pr. DS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Probably a Franklin imprint
    With this is an engraving of Dr. Franklin in fur cap. Removed from frame; Feb. 1963.
  - Bond of Mary Middleton, Benjamin Franklin and Jacob Duché in re estate of James Middleton, 1745 June 3; DS, 1p.; Middleton, Mary
  - Letter to James Alexander, 1745 August 15; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Relative to some engraving work. Mentions [Lewis ?] Evans and [James ?] Parker.
    Printed: Labaree, Works, III, 32. Cannot find in print - 6/44.
  - Bond to Isaac Jones, 1745 December 19; Photo., 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Robert B. Fisher; 1961.
    General note
    (see film 1052.)
  - [Bond in re administration of estate of Joseph Breintnall], 1746 April 12; DS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to [William Strahan], 1746 May 22; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Orders maps for Assembly.
    Printed in part: Smyth 2, 297. Printed: Labaree, Works, III, 77.
  - Letter to Brother [Franklin], 1747 April 2; LS Cy, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    On same sheet is portion of another, undated, letter from Franklin to his brother. Desires information on Admiral Warren's actions. Mentions Billy [William Franklin].
    Printed: Labaree, Works III,119.
  - Letter to William Strahan, 1747 June 1; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Mr. Hall will advise him of their business arrangement. Purchase of books.
    Printed: Labaree, Works, III, 140.
  - Letter to W[illia]m Strahan, 1747 November 28; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Mr. Hall will order books for the shop after that date. Maps for the gallery and assembly room in the State House. Presented by Dr. Thomas S. Gates, May 1947.
  - List of debts due sundry persons, ca.1747; AMs, 1p.; Meuris, Matthias. Estate of
    Debt to Benjamin Franklin - £42.
  - Letter to Cadwalader Colden, 1748 Sept. 29; Photostat, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From Original in the New-York Historical Society.
    Printed: Smyth, v.2,p.362. Labaree, Works, III, 317-320.
  - Letter to Mr. Strahan, 1748 November 23; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Relative to Mr. Read's account. Mentions Dr. Mitchell and fireplaces.
    Presented by J. B. Nolan from original in Buffalo Historical Society, November 1948.
    Printed: Labaree, Works, III, 326-327.
  - Minutes, 1748 November 7; 1748 Dec.; 1748/9 January 9; 3p.; Library Company of Philadelphia.
    Dr. of A.D. in handwriting of Benjamin Franklin.
    On reverse of bill for books from Peter Collinson, June 16,1742-Oct. 15, 1745.
  - Letter to Ja[mes Logan ?], 1749 July 4; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Sends Smith's Travels and Pope's Life of Ward. Mentions N. Holland.
    Printed: Labaree, Works, III, 382.
  - Letter to [George Whitefield], 1749 July 6; A.L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Fragment.
    Printed: Smyth, II, 377-378; London Evangelical Magazine, XI, (1803), 27-8. Labaree, Works, III, 382-383.
  - Account with T. Leech and B. Franklin, 1749 Sept. 29-1751 April 24; 1751 August 6; DS. 1p.; Koyle, Michael, Estate of
    In Franklin's hand. Principally funeral expenses and taxes.
  - Letter to [Abiah Folger Franklin], 1749 Sept. 7; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In hand of Jane Mecom.
    Presented by Morris Duane; Dec 1962.
    Printed: Labaree, Papers,vol.3,388-89.
  - Inventory of estate, 1749 October 6; D, 1p.; Koyle, Michael
    In B. Franklin's hand.
  - Letter to "Dear Elias", 1750 June 1; Photocopy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Acknowledges receipt of the "copper and Worm" which is to be forwarded to an individual in Maryland. Mentions James Logan.
    (From Sotheby Parke Bernet Inc., Public Auction, May 21, 1974.)
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin]; Lond[on], 1750 July 10 [or 11]; Photostat, 3p.; Collinson Peter, 1694-1768
    The proprietor approves the Academy. All of his electrical papers are in press under the supervision of Dr. Fothergill. Mentions John Bartram.
    From original on Library Co.
  - Minutes, 1750 Sept. 10; 1p.; Library Company of Philadelphia.
    Oct. 8. A.D. in hand of B. Franklin.
  - Letter to [William Strahan], 1750 December 6; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Asks that he enter his son, William Franklin, as a student of law in one of the Inns; orders some books.
    Printed: Labaree, Papers, vol.IV, 77f.
  - Receipt to B. Franklin for certain books and magazines for the library, 1750 Dec. 22; DS, 1p.; Lavers, Robert
  - Receipt to Benjamin Franklin for payment of tax for Michael Koyall's estate, 1751 June 6; DS, 1p.; Hurford, Samuel
  - Letter to [Peter Collinson], 1751 July 29 (?); ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Comment on Albany conference from which has just returned, Finds is Beccaria's Dell'elettricismo artificiale naturale that the author has same opinion as he does that "Thunder-Storkes are sometimes upwards from the earth to the cloud."
    Contains note in Collinson's hand. Transcribed also is letter from Franklin to Collinson, May 28, 1754, in secretary's hand.
    Printed: Cohen, I. B., Franklin and Newton. v.43. p. 500-501. (Extracts): Labaree, Papers, vol.V,394-396.
  - Letters to [Cadwallader Colden], 1751 October 31; Lithograph (?) of ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed under date of 1751; Smyth, 5.34.
  - Rules to be accepted by members.., 1752 April 24; Photostat, Forgery; The Philadelphians chess society
  - 1752 July 7, D.S, 9 leaves.; Philadelphia. Mayor, Magistrates and Wardens
    Orders for regulating the conduct of the watch, made by the magistrates and wardens.
    Printed: Labaree, Papers, vol.IV,327-332.
  - Mortgage from Thomas and Martha Green to Isaac Norris, Thomas Leech and Edward Warner, for parcel of land in Northern Liberties, £179.17.10, 1752 August 4; D.S. 3p.; Green, Thomas
    Certification, August 21, 1752, S: B. Franklin, as justice.
    Presented by Mr. Samuel H. Mcvitty, March 1955.
  - Letter to [William Strahan], 1752 Sept. 1; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Encloses second bill for £20 drawn on Alexander Grant for Mary Stevens.
    For record of first bill, see letter of Aug. 8, 1752 (Smyth, III,94). Fine impression of B.F.'s seal.
    Printed:Labaree, Papers, vol.IV, 354.
  - Letter to P[eter] Collinson, 1752 October 1; Enlargement pprint of copy of L. 2p., end.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Copy made by Peter Collinson.
    Presented by I.B. Cohen, March 1952, from original owned by Royal Society.
    Printed: Royal Society, Phil. Trans. v.47, 565; Smyth v.1,99 under date of October 19, 1752.
  - Letter to John Franklin, 1752 December 8; Photostat, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Pertains to a catheter.
    Photostat presented by the New York Academy of Medicine which owns the original.
    Printed: Smyth, v.3, 103.
  - Petition against patent exclusive rights of trade to Labrador, 1752; Photostat, 2p.; Philadelphia. Merchants
    Also contains report of the Lords of the committee of council for plantation affairs; December 21, 1752.
    Original in the Colonial office of the board of trade - commercial.
    Printed: Solis- Cohen, Phila's expedition to Labrador, Penne.Hict., v.19, 156-157.
  - Letter to "Dear Brother" [John Franklin ?], 1753 January 2; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Questions him about their father's estate; and about various papers on electricity etc., he sent him. On reverse is copy of letter from Franklin to his brother, Sept. 27, 1750.
    From original in possession of Vassar B. Carlton, who presented photostat, May 1951.
  - Letter to Brother [John (?) Franklin], 1753 January 2; LS Cy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    His brother's case of the stone. Questions concerning their father's estate. Inquires whether he has read his electrical papers and others sent him.
  - Deed, given by his attorney Samuel Preston Moore to Samuell Powell, for plot of ground about Third and Sassafras streets, 1753 March 25; 2p.; Hill, Richard
    D. with certification S: B. Franklin, Justice. April 20,1753.
  - Deed to Moses Moore for land in Chester Co., Pa, 1753 May 18; DS, 1p.; Norris, Isaac, 1701-1766
  - Letter to [Peter Collinson], 1753 May 9; LS Cy, 7p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Arthur Bloch, Nov.1954.
    Printed in various versions: Van Doren, Franklin-Jackson, p.33 Aldridge in APS Proceedings, v.94, no.4 Smyth (to R. Jackson), 3,133 Sparks, 7,166; Labaree, Papers, vol.IV, 477ff.
  - Letter to George Whitefield, Philadelphia, 1753 June 6; Photostat, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Franklin's notion of good works.
    The Franklin Papers contain an autograph draft of this letter, with slight differences in wording, addressed to Joseph Huey (v.45, no.7); see also Smyth, v.3,143)
    The original of this photostat was offered for sale to the A.P.S. by Paul Elder and Co., San Francisco, Cal., March 1940.
  - Letter to Hugh Roberts. Philadelphia, 1753 July 16; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Forwards package for the Speaker. Concerning his travels and plans for return. Refers to the Junto.
    Presented by R. Sturgis Ingersoll; July 12, 1951.
    Printed: Labaree, Papers,vol.V,11-12.
  - Minute of the Directors, 1753 December 10; A.D. in hand of B. Franklin 2p.; Library Company of Philadelphia.
    Presented By Mr. S.H. McVitty, March 1955.
  - Letter to Edw[ar]d Shippen, 1754 February 14; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printing house in Lancaster.
    Printed: Labaree, Papers, vol.V, 198-199.
  - Letter to [William Watson], 1754 April 19; Photostat; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Electrical experiments.
    From original consigned to A.Privat, Paris, 1949.
    Printed:Cohen, I. B. Franklin and Newton p.502-503: Labaree, Papers, V,265-6.
  - Letter to President and Council of the Royal Society [ of London], 1754 May 19; Typed c. of L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Acknowledges the honor bestowed upon him by receipt of the Copley medal for 1753.
    Presented by I. Bernard Cohen, Sept. 1951.
  - Letter to [Peter Collinson], 1754 May 28; Copy of L. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Proprietor's interest in the Academy. Sent paper containing his new experiments on lightning and electricity of the clouds. Capt. Swain has gone on second attempt for the N.W. passage. Acknowledges [Copley] medal and barometers through Mr. Smith. Mr. Short's improvements of his fire-hearths. Comments on relationship of the Crown and colonies with respect to the designs of the French. Albany conference.
    On same sheet with letter of July 29, 1754.
    Printed (extracts): Cohen, I. B. Franklin and Newton, pp. 499-500: Labaree, Papers, vol. V, 330-333.
  - Letter to William Strahan, 1755 March 23; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790